but you can't polish a turd that much
but I
marketplace probably speaks for itself
I've listened to a lot of podcasts that
I make it about 5 minutes and 26 seconds
into and I'm like yep it hurts my ears
I'm in the car and there's like six
people there so I mean so they're
invested they're doing it and and I have
matters Beckett so many of you have
heard podcast yeah I just did my first
my first three-person well okay so there
was one time where I did a foreperson
but it was at the very beginning and I
was very kind of casual like dipping my
toes in and it was just one for way yeah
every way yes yes yeah you got it you
know you got to do the little foreplay
before you go all the way in but so I
did the first three one just me and two
DJ's and I was like okay this is cool it
set up I like scooted this whole table
out here and and headed up the way it
was two of their mics were like looped
into the same track when I went to edit
it and one of them was way farther away
from the mic than the other one so I'm
just like and it's it sounds totally
fine nobody would really care but you
know it's something that I want to
challenge myself to improve and in work
on my audio engineering you know I want
to I want to like have little stuff like
that that I didn't expect have to come
up and then still try to make it sound
the best that I can
you know right right so you so you can
actually isolate one voice and like
increase the volume on it or yeah but
but the way that I had did it it pretty
much pasted it like it was done it was
already the waveform and so I can't just
separate it when they're both talking so
what I would do is is that would just
follow along and I listen to it and I
would kind of draw along when one guy's
talking I make it louder one guy's not
talking you know so it's it's a little
tedious but it's it's kind of one of
those things where it's these learning
experiences like oh you should have done
better you should have it set up a
little bit better and this would have
been easy for you bro so it's it's not
like punishment it's it's enjoyable cuz
I like to know dude it's the journey
yeah it's the journey I mean that's what
that's that's the bit of advice I'll
never forget from you is when you told
me in the store when you're asking about
your senior speech yeah you told me
everyone forgets to enjoy the journey
and that plays an eye and I'm not
kidding I'm not over exaggerating I bet
I bet that plays in my mind once a week
minimum minimum that's the impact if I
enjoyed it because I will have all
always been very motivated so I've
always feel like I'm moving towards the
next thing and I say this a lot I'm
always like hey you know when we're
young we want to be 16 then we want to
be 18 mm-hm and then we want to be 21
and then all of a sudden I'm like 26 I'm
like whoa yeah slow down like yeah and
and you were you were pushing so hard to
hit these milestones and then you passed
the milestones and you're like wait a
second there was a lot of time there
that I should have probably just been
living in the present yeah I forgot to
check out those roses man oh the typical
it's funny the old cliche sayings you
know that I remember there was one that
you said to me that I always I actually
always remember I think I said it in a
couple of podcasts already was you can't
win a lottery if you don't buy a lottery
ticket yeah you told me that it could
have been the same conversation which
would be super dope too but we you see
so so Bob is it Kendall or Ken doll how
do you say your last name Kendall
Kendall okay so we met at fuel munition
you were the the buyer what was your job
title technically I was men's buyer MIT
men's buyer but I did everything from
merchandising to to buying to a lot of
the data analytics and stuff like that
so which is kind of like a new his face
that I it was like a nice thing of a
smaller business yeah I was able to wear
many hats learn many things how many
stores did it was fuel munition they
changed an empty munition but it was how
many stores you remember eight stores
hey stores yeah and I remember you you
were the one who would like drop by drop
off shipment see how the employees are
doing come hang out like you would come
it's it that's why I was excited I
texted you the other day and I don't
even think I said hey what's up man I
was just like hey bro podcast like
you're like what's up how are ya let's
do this yeah well because every time
that we would get together like you it
you would come down just to check on the
store whatever and I think we would end
up just talking and you know sometimes
it would be a little dead and we would
end up just talking for two hours and
stuff talking about life you dude you're
you're an intellectual I always feel
like I have a lot to learn from you so
it's cool to have you on the podcast and
introduce you to people who may listen
so if you want to give a lowdown of who
you are and where you're at that's
that's a pretty deep question actually
really yeah do you know the one I didn't
who am i yes what is well man there's a
lot of substance there
but I've had a lot I've genuinely been
able to experience a lot of things I
spent many many years in the apparel
industry that was always my passion and
my that contributing in a way where
people get to express themselves by
wearing something it's a staple in all
of our lives it's something that maybe
some people don't think about but it's
something that visually I feel like is a
larger impact than a lot of people
really really give give weight to and
being able to follow trends and talk to
people and genuinely see how the things
people wore affected their lives was was
something that we always felt I always
felt that if I could make if I could
make you happy just the experience and
coming in the store whether you bought
anything or not that the success was
going to be a byproduct and just giving
people a place to come and feel better
about themselves on the way out the door
was really the the ultimate goal your
personnel be yes it comes across very
well yeah definitely so so you worked in
the apparel industry and that's
definitely when we met and you were how
old were you when he like first started
with yeah definitely 16 do you remember
like your first like I just imagine you
probably have some sort of like hustle
story of how you got into your first job
well so so actually I did I made all the
mistakes so I I showed up to the
interview and a baseball cap and jeans
oh man and in all fairness I was coming
straight from school and I'd convinced
the owner to give me a shot to give me
an interview
I called probably 25 plus times to the
corporate office and it would just kept
going to voicemail and when we I don't
know if you remember they they built
this in our nice little mall that we
have over there in Kelso they built this
wall around it's actually had multiple
misspellings which is kind of funny but
they built this wall around like coming
soon fuel and everyone is up in arms
like that's where they wanted to work
like that was the cool thing to do was
to work at the low top of the loop I was
like 13 or 14 when it first opened so so
I was like freshly freshly 16 and and I
I knew that's what I wanted to do
I wanted to work at the other local
board shop actually the boardroom for
many years and I'd gone in there and
probably bugged but the guys who worked
there to the point of where they're like
yeah yeah sure we'll hire you whenever
we hire sure whatever here to take a
free poster and get out of here and he
actually hired his wife and I remember
just being devastated like oh my gosh
this was like picking favorites me she
sucks yeah come on dude what she know
and so so I got this opportunity and and
I turned in my resume and the Moloch
everyone did and then I just kept
calling and calling and and I think that
they picked up the phone by accident and
the lady's like oh uh okay yeah what
works for an interview and I guess
that'll work and so I got there and and
she said the reason she hired me is
because I was engaged I leaned forward I
listened I did things that that you know
so it came down to like kind of the
social skills of like him seeing that I
really wanted this and the owner used to
tell everyone this story constantly when
I when I was his buyer that the first
day he actually told his wife to to let
me go I was very quiet I was very
introverted way after all this you're
quiet and I calling the Moga I'm like
I'm shy developed it all I wasn't
motivated but I've also like I was also
very introverted like I didn't feel like
I really needed to fit in with anybody
in high school like then I was just kind
of me I was very quiet I absorbed his
because you were like a you were a
skateboarder for sure right but but you
kind of did just float along I guess you
weren't like a skateboard clique or what
I've always been me I mean I never felt
like I really needed to fit into one
slot like I feel like you get one shot
at this life thing like and a lot of
people are so worried about I can't try
this or I can't go out for this or I
can't do this and and not that I'm
perfect and not that I didn't fall into
some of those some of those things in my
life but I always kind of wanted to just
try new things like I joined the
football team when I was a sophomore in
high school and I got the crap kicked
out of me but I stuck with it all season
but um and realize that that was not for
me but I wanted to give it a shot you
know what I mean I wanted to get out
there and actually experience what what
this really was and why it why all the
hype and and I like to I like to go into
things and I
a couple practices in the coaches like
have you even ever watched a
professional football game I'm like well
you know I watch the Super Bowl and in
the commercials our cynic right I am
every conversation so did you so you
just got whomped the first you remember
what position you played tight end okay
dude what can you explain what tight end
is real quick
oh no not not even a little bit no I was
gonna I would say kind of confident but
I was they got it it's okay to be like I
don't know I was gonna ask no it looked
like that guy got tackled the least and
so that I was like that looks like the
position for me when creators want to
play football on tractors what you play
football
I'm just trying it out I mean that's
that's kind of who we are though that's
I definitely like that about you as just
trying new things and you're just that's
what Shaylee said when she I told her
that you coming over today and she was
like oh yeah he's such a good he's very
well driven and he's always trying new
things entrepreneur wise and I'm like
yes that's so true so so there's the
store at the mall yes it distorts so I
got hired ok owner wanted to fire me and
as his wife's like no no no he's such a
nice guy he won't steal from us at least
so I had that that's the soy at back dog
bar yeah so um turned out when they
brought me in the first day they're like
pass out raffle tickets we really don't
think you're gonna you know like he gave
me pretty much the crummy like oh go
clean the bathroom too before you pass
out raffle it's a kills no sign it do
but I have my foot in the door I was
like I'm in the bathrooms whatever I
wouldn't clean the bathrooms probably
the best bathrooms ever looked I handed
out those raffle tickets until my hands
were orange and then I hit the sales
floor cuz I knew that that was where I
could where I could actually continue to
grow and I became the top selling
salesperson in the first two months I
worked easily quickly what location did
then this was the legation Kelso yeah
yeah yeah me and Craig Marshall oh man
that sounds membersí Marsh yeah I went
to our long I mean the name totally
sounds to me I may put put a face to it
but so ok so that's so dope so you work
there how many years I'm wondering to
think of like around it when it was when
I would have been there so I graduated
2010 and I worked at PacSun was my first
job when it was
the day I turn 16 and then I'd worked
there for tax on first well so so the
manager of munition who actually like
sniped me from PacSun so okay so my pack
sons story I started out from PacSun
what I would do is I was also a mall rat
and I was in a position in my life like
as much as I thought it was so cool to
work at PacSun I was also in this like
weird position at home where I needed a
job I was like starting to like things
are I'm on my own you know I need money
yeah and so I luckily I had the brains
to like why don't I do something that I
like and so I went to PacSun and I would
go in there and I'd set my skateboard in
my in my backpack outside and I would
check on my resume you know I got to the
point where I was just joking and I was
annoying and like they had come in and
she's like we're not hiring you know
we're not hiring yeah Jake and whatever
but so what I did though to keep proving
myself I hope that I'm not like miss
remembering this and thinking that I'm
way cooler than I am I always forget
that but a whatever Matt for man right
make yourself sound cooler because
nobody else can tell them but it's a
podcast in my hometown that I still live
in hilarious I can't lie
but no anyway so so what I would do is I
would put my bag outside and then I
would go convince one of the managers to
let me sell to a customer to prove it so
that was my calling a ton of times and
so I'm like no I trust me like I would
and I wouldn't say anything obviously
like off the wall or I wouldn't be a
jackass of course but I would just go
talk to people because I like I like
learning about people and I like I I
genuinely enjoyed you know I have always
complimented people on their attire
because I generally enjoy when other
people are wearing something it's just
like hey you get it like I know that you
feel that on the inside and you kind of
want to express it on the outside a
little bit this is my winking at you and
me winking at you as saying like hey man
or we like those shoes it's just yeah
it's it's it's great I really like it
it's just like this little wink you know
kind of you know bike riders have their
wave and gee people have their little
it's a Jeep thing it just seems like
that to me anyway but em so it was
really natural and I enjoyed doing it I
enjoyed selling and worked there for a
year and met Shaylee hit on her a lot
and
and I got sniped it was like offered
better it was probably like a twelve
centuries or something but I was like
this is moving up it's moving up so I
want to say that we might have like I
don't know if it was just on paper we
called assistant manager something maybe
for fuel okay I don't know if we even
had assistant manager position I say it
was a smaller company but hey my resume
says the system and Rik's I did system
had your stuff that's the show right is
that kind of funny how we have to just
we're like I don't know I did these
things and they're like oh that means
this you're like we say so yeah I know
all about it I own my own business
and a lot of people look at that oh
you're the owner oh so you did nothing
it's like using tele to narrow it all
down well no one's there to vouch for
you at that point yeah they're like okay
yeah cool sure all right okay well okay
so it's giving forward owning own
business
so we met through munition I had worked
there for a little bit we had become
like kind of friends whatever and then
time moved on a few years and then you
opened up to cutting-edge mm-hmm you
want to talk about that well I'm sure
you remember the day that I gave my my
notice that I tell me all about it so so
I'd been a buyer the sales floor had
really taught me like social skills
right which I think which is the part
that I was getting too but I was taking
way too long to get to the this the
sales floor was good because it was that
trial and error of what if I what if I
stick my foot in my mouth and what I
mean what whatever I learned from that I
move on and I see what works with people
and the same with you let me try to sell
to someone let me try a lot of people
can't ever cross that barrier mm-hm and
I think that that's a really important
thing for to just just do things right
just just experience things here they're
not all gonna be good things but you can
take them as learning experiences you
can turn them into good things you hear
a lot of famous people say that all the
time that my mistakes are no longer
mistakes if I learn from them and and we
have that power and a lot of people may
not ever get there but it's something
that I keep in my mind all the time like
I'm gonna make mistakes I either own
them and learn from them
or I let them tear me down right I think
we get stopped with I'm introvert like
you just said like you're you're kind of
shy right what I like so I'm shy that
called me silent bob high school oh
that's hilarious actually
oh that's not right layers I'm sorry
just give me the look
but it is funny because we something
that I had to deal with with my
depression was something it seems so
obvious and you don't just just a
sentence of like you can get better
we sometimes we're like well I'm
depressed you understand or I'm this in
your Center I'm shine you understand I'm
introvert you don't understand and we
leave it at that and we sit with that
and we can't fight who we are of course
we have to like bring that with us and
everything that we do but a lot of a lot
of your life is on the other side of the
things that terrify you
and so yeah yeah exactly and you have to
fight back and even fighting back to me
is even you know like you know not just
depression or anxiety or you're feeling
sad it's it's I wonder what this life
could be like I wonder it you were like
I wonder if I could work here like that
could be a crazy place to work I'm
pretty shy but like I bet I could do
that pretty good so you have this itch
you have no idea how to do any of that
crap you don't know anything about that
but you're like you have this one thing
that's all you had to follow wasn't that
one intuition of like dude just call him
well 25 intuitions of dude just call him
again but but just going for it and
pushing past like the you know the the
introverted Ness you know for me I think
a lot of my pushing out of introverted
miss was a survival technique but I mean
it shaped me into Who I am I mean it's
absolutely like I have one of the most
chameleon personalities and and I used
to you know think that I was like
changing Who I am and not being
authentic when I was talking to certain
people used to make me a little sad I
was like I don't know who I am Mike I'm
always kind of acting a little different
around other people but it's it's
because you know when you grow up in
these environments and you grow up like
thrown to the wolves and even the
exciting things of like you're 15 or 16
and you're interacting with a new type
of person multiple times it's it's
you're like oh here's a grandma right
here and then right behind that grandma
is some kid who's 16 and he's got 4
bucks he's going to get
sticker but you wanted you want to treat
him with respect to because he's looking
up to you you know like just because
grandma has the most money in front of
him doesn't mean that you're not gonna
equally learn something from from
selling to this kid so well and
communicating with people I think that
we we get it we get it twisted like that
grandma needs something different then
and I can supply that to her without
losing Who I am like yeah social skills
are really I feel my opinion continues
to be that social skills are the most
important the skill to develop for
everyone right because you can and you
can do a lot about what's in here but
and you can do almost nothing about
what's out here but the more you develop
this the more you elevate what's inside
yeah and your heart it tends to make
things better
on the outside yeah start here if you
work on this if you continue that to
elevate this and to and I think social
skills is a big part of that and helps
you pull out of it working retail was
was a a great thing for me in my life
because it really taught me a lot about
you know assessing the situation and and
being able to get make that person's
life a little bit better if you could
it's kind of that service right like you
know is that that word is sometimes
taken away with let's say religion for
in my head anyway
sure like be of service um but but
taking that word back a little bit it is
you know you're like I'm introvert in
what I really want us to stay in the
back room and just text my best friend
but what what's got what's gonna be
great is if I gives us the in it's easy
and it's in its what what's scary is
outside right what's what's scary is is
that person you're like what if they're
mean to me what if I suck at selling
it's all these things yeah what if they
open it up so let's just switch spaces
what do you think about aliens yeah well
okay so we were just talking about your
company though so so jumping from yeah
so which I know nothing about okay but I
knew that I had always wanted to do
something myself and and I really
thoroughly enjoyed apparel
I could see the writing on the wall 2008
happened and the market collapse well so
I remember this very distinctly we came
in and we had a meeting that day and I
think there was even a newspaper sitting
there again maybe I'm mister presenting
the facts but this is I'll give you the
blow-by-blow of what is great yeah
that's Helen and the newspaper sitting
there with the article of the stock
market and all this stuff right and I
remember the owner saying cancel every
pretty book we have this is the worst
thing that ever happened like just total
panic did you follow like stocks in
money and that sort of thing like was
that just like I don't know much about
this vaguely okay vaguely
a little little bit yeah yeah and enough
to know that we had like our own kind of
ecosystem in our own like economy and if
we panicked and if we cancelled every
pre-booked and that was a
self-fulfilling prophecy I knew that
that was the my judgment told me that
that was that what was gonna happen and
sure enough I mean three months later
they pull me in and like hey look I told
you we're way down in sales and I'm like
well we could sell everything in the
store tomorrow that we'd still be 30%
down I mean that this is a
self-fulfilling you cancelled all our
new stock coming in and then you wonder
it and then you wonder why our sales are
down I think that I think that they took
this kind of overall and I think a lot
of people do this oh my god who's who's
president oh my god whose Supreme Court
justice oh my and they forget that
really like yes that stuff matters sure
but but we forget to really look inside
and be like what's what's gonna affect
me directly what if I can't do anything
about that genuinely if I'm not gonna
stop if I'm not gonna derail everything
and dedicate my life to focusing on that
one problem or what I first see is a
problem then then I really again need to
go inwards and say how can I continue to
make my situation better what can what
can we do in a reasonable way cancelling
all of our stock coming in obvious
was not he has not the correct it just
means he don't get more stock so anyway
it seems pretty basic math to me and I
did at the time but everyone has their
motives everyone has their you know yeah
I mean yeah there could have been so
much more than well so I felt when I
when I had the opportunity to come back
and manage the store I had not ever had
the official title of manager and and I
wanted I really wanted the opportunity
to come back and show them that we could
do better right so I don't know if you
remember but I mean we were within the
first 30 days and it grew up like 40
percent yeah cuz you came back as just a
location over this door just the basics
yeah I'm dumb enough to know that if any
other human being can do anything that I
can do it right think of this that and
and that's and that's kind of how I've
always viewed things is that if anybody
else can do it I am also a human being I
also have the same potential to do this
thing and doesn't mean I'm gonna
dedicate as much time and effort and and
whatever and succeed in that area
possibly not but but if they can do it I
can do it yeah it always made you a good
salesperson too because I was I always
loved you know I thought I was hotshot
you know so it's funny I always I always
say I was catching myself saying that
I'm not competitive because I never
played organized sports I wasn't ever
like sports like it was skateboarding
like I don't care what you're doing I
just want to do the nicest kickflip
everyone listen to my music in my
headphones you know I was never
competitive with much but I think as
we're talking like watching you sell or
like watching the way that you're like
just watch and you just would go do this
thing you know like you come through and
I I don't remember exactly what I feel
like you'd probably like retrained a few
of us in some sort of way it's like just
by coming in it took a lot of trial and
error man that did that didn't come
naturally to me that took years and
years of being out on the floor and
seeing what worked and seeing what and
and I was genuine time I see product and
that by the time I see it you're natural
right yeah and you'll see the final
right so you're polishing LeBron Tamiya
but that's the thing is also being
passionate about the product is that was
a huge thing that I learned from you
that I always pass on to anybody in
retail that I know
you know young kids in any advice is
learn about the product because not only
does it make you love it
the more it makes you be able to explain
it to the customer it makes you be able
to know what you're selling them like if
they if they happen to not kill animals
and you know this person looks like they
they care about that sort of thing it's
something that you're gonna mention you
know it's it's not not meant to be I'm
no way on know yeah craft right hone
your craft right and I don't know why I
went to killing animals I just want to
read I can't just do the ship they're
like yeah bro I don't know I was
thinking of like Toms where they donate
yeah I think like like that's genuinely
great when people would come in to buy
Tom's it's like I honestly want to sell
you Tom's because I think they're
awesome
you know I think what they stand for is
awesome and so you learn more about them
I think Tom's fundamentally changed the
way that Tom's businesses like Tom's
actually fundamentally changed the way
that at least the consumer that was
within their demographic the purchased
because it made them conscious of what
they were buying it masked an additional
question yeah and it was a question of
is what I'm doing I'm creating a bigger
impact than myself and I think that
that's a hard question to turn off I
think that once a consumer goes there
that they that they continue to ask
themselves whether or not that drives to
all of their purchasing decisions at
least in our niche I think that it
caused people to ask additional
questions about you know I love Nike
shoes but our kids are our kids really
stitching them in some warehouse
somewhere and yeah that's what I'm doing
enabling that or is what I'm doing yeah
everybody into something theater these
are things that it's like yeah once you
learn that information you can't really
just pretend to not know it and it's you
know it does feel good saying you know
there's something that I just learned
about and I could do a little bit you
know for example Shaylee brings metal
straws everywhere that we go and she's
like I know it's not much but it's it's
a couple less plastic straws that are
being used
seems like plastic isn't isn't super
great for the world so I like how I get
my paper straw on a giant plastic cup
though that always in a disarray it's
what's happening but they're like we're
just doing the effort and we're like but
the point
the thematic of what you doing and so
you had the business cutting edge yeah
now that was cool what what kind of
let's so anybody who doesn't know any
listeners who weren't familiar let's
tell what kind of clothing that we sold
that munition and then I cutting it
action sports lifestyle apparel footwear
accessories kind of demographic was like
that 18 mm more like probably 13 to
early 20s right yeah I'd say so so you
know it wasn't all skateboarding
necessarily along has a lifestyle yeah
and when I branched off to cutting edge
I wanted to explore more like the you
know it was something new and exciting
to me I could do whatever I wanted with
it I could bring in whatever brand I
wanted so I tried some some like MMA
some lifestyle some we actually did very
very well with our high-end denim yeah
that was very trendy well yeah that was
at that point it's kind of funny now
because I'm not sure if they're as as
trendy there might just be a whole
demographic that I'll see ya but because
I'm not into the retail world now but
hey that was was as far as styles ago
you definitely have that that lockdown
in our town style too
yeah around here you know that was
definitely you know well we were able to
hone in on things I'd worked in this
specific area for so long that I was
lucky enough to have a lot of knowledge
about what people are coming and looking
for and so so branching off and sir
yeah I I had no idea if anybody was ever
gonna walk through my doors and I'm I
don't think there's been anything in my
life besides probably having my children
that has made me physically shake but I
remember the first person that came in
and bought something and it could have
been because we pulled an all-nighter to
get open to but the first person that
bought something I physically was like
my hands were shaking that's what
it was with that it was yeah it was a
beanie yes yeah I setup I had no hat
display so last minute I brought in an
artificial Christmas tree and said all
my hats around and everyone thought was
genius because it was the holidays so
everyone called it yeah I had a plan to
get in the window you could see it in
that yeah people is yeah I loved I loved
the
displays their I remember it was always
cool to like redo the displays and then
we would send him out to you guys and
send him to the other stores I could the
other stores would send display ideas
around and it was always really cool to
it my favorite part of the job was
merchandising absolutely I whether I own
my own business or whether it was fuel
when it what and even in buying what in
buying what I do is I would ask the
vendor for like three catalogs I would
have one catalogue that I would just cut
every picture of the items out and I
would lay it all out on the table and
I'd merchandise per month what what
matched what and what looked good with
what and put outfits together and and
and put together display ideas and I've
never been very I feel like I've got a
lot of artistic thoughts but actually
pulling them out of my body and putting
onto anything right is like something
that maybe I never exercised enough it
feels very foreign to me it'd be like me
trying to sit here and write a sentence
in Spanish it's it's not gonna happen
it's not gonna be legible okay so but in
my mind I was always very good at
putting things together having clear
concise any any brand I've ever worked
with where I like I really love the
creative behind apparel I love the
creative I love the I love the idea of
being able to put something together
that that appeals to people and that and
that yeah yeah dude me too that's
exactly how I am it's cool when you
finally find some some outlet to like
you probably were never expecting when
you're this introverted guy who's just
calling a much time to get this cool job
you think you never expected to to
realize that you're like oh this is a
creative outlet for me you know I know
all humans have to me I think all humans
have
I wanted it pretty cool I wanted to sell
skate right and then when I got into the
mic wait this clothing stuff is pretty
awesome and then when I when I went to
Vegas to the trade shows it was like
game over the first trade show I ever
went to was in Hood River and I remember
they asked me and I used to ice I'd skip
school or I would I had a job at the
hospital I'd skip that
I would if the owners were coming I was
going to be at the store whether I was
scheduled or not I was gonna load the
stock in I was gonna talk you smoothies
in front of them yeah yeah like and
because I knew that this just out of an
entrepreneur that's what I wanted to do
right and I remember the first trade
show they asked me to go to they just
asked me to come as a guest and kind of
see if if I wanted to do this and the
first we sat down and looked at etnies
etnies shoes we Brad knees
yes I did we sat down we looked at at
NIEHS shoes and I smell something when I
think of anything just because I walked
in the rain with just like dirty ed
knees are so lucky that everybody had
like you say anything I'm just like I
smell with that music so I looked down
and I literally was looking at Footwear
I had a Sharpie in my hand and was
marking in a catalogue what I thought
would sell and I'm like this is what I'm
going to do with the rest of my life
epik like hand me shoes and ask me if
they're cool like that and then and I'll
give you my opinion and then the longer
I got into it the more excited I was
because I realized my opinion didn't
matter that it really was that it really
was more about the the marketplace right
and and learning what people saw and why
they saw it but that in a way that they
didn't even realize was was going on
right it kind of changes your your
reality a little I mean that's intense
but it changes the way when you walk
around at the mall you you see things in
a different sense than than shoppers do
yeah absolutely
trying to get inside consumers heads is
um was exciting and and it changed every
day
every day there was something new every
day there was something different
and we didn't stay on one idea or one
concept or one thing too long because
the marketplace is so fast we were
always six months ahead at least where I
was looking at new things we were always
and it's funny because all these brands
obviously communicator I'll go off the
same stuff because one year they'd all
have plaid or one year they'd all have
you know and so I was exciting to see
like things change and ideas come around
that you're like no way well that
and sure enough you you start selling it
you couldn't get enough of it you know
what I mean like it was I mean ok so
what do you think about some of the it's
it's hard to not see some of the trends
from the younger kids because I I've
followed trends I enjoy a lot of trends
I'm just I'm a fan of pop culture I
think I think humans in in what we do
with culture and in fashion especially
is the most cool thing like it's just
I'm obsessed with it but I do notice
that you know when I get a little more
lately for example less on social media
a little less connected from a lot of
the music I've been DJing a lot less I
don't really watch much TV
I'm just getting disconnected so I feel
like I'm starting to see some of the
trends from the outside maybe I'm on the
back half of them or I'm not really
following them as much it made me that's
just getting older really that's like a
fashionable dude but um do you the
trends the trends are cool to see yeah
do you see anything that's like way
different now because now we have
technology we have less of the human eye
now we have more of the decisions being
made by a lot of this stuff I fear that
is probably a lot less artistic
decisions and more like oh kids from
this rural area like this based off
these statistics that we pulled from
their Instagram algorithms you know what
I mean so so much more insight yeah with
social media than there was I mean it
was MySpace back in our day and no one
had really computed like put that
together in a way that made any any
sense to anybody other than it was just
random stuff being thrown at the wall
and you can't do anything with that
information now you we can't have a
conversation and not see six ads about
it when I get on Facebook oh my you know
it so it they they have it so computed
and so it's it's a different landscape
and sure and Instagram influencer could
come on tomorrow and set a trend I mean
it's it's so much different than like
them looking out for so long and I think
that's why you started seeing big
companies do things like quick releases
or or drops or they realized our window
to react to these things is so much
smaller and it's they need to be able to
jump on something right now versus
something used to happen in Europe and
then it's slowly trickled over to East
Coast and then it slowly trickled over
to
California and then it slowly trickled
back up to us yeah and and I don't think
it's that way anymore because now
someone can mass be like hey check out
these kicks on Instagram and it gets so
many likes that all the shoe companies
are probably like oh crap right like oh
we need a rest were Gaia Sheen like yeah
I mean that's how it is I mean there's
there's probably crazy amounts of
companies now that their job they
probably have let's say giant office
buildings it's just people surfing the
internet waiting for trends to hit so
they're the first ones to hit or even to
influence trends influence when I was
sir so when I when I shut down my our
stores when the writing was on the wall
kind of for BC malls that consumers kind
of changed the way they they shopped and
they and did things one of the first
things I did was besides going out and
get my real estate license and and
trying to figure out where I wanted to
go and experience and and a totally
shift gears into something new and
different and diversify myself a little
bit I felt like I was so honed in on
this one thing that was my passion and
my goal and I wanted to make sure that I
wasn't missing missing anything
in a way that was still responsible and
and still true to myself but I started
sales reppin for Solon which was is like
a tattoo artist I forgot about that
actually so that was cool mm-hmm and man
that I got to experience some really
cool things it just happenstance the
sales manager at the time calls me like
it was like 10:30 on a Monday night and
he's like dude third flight just got
canceled I need you to go pitch this
brand to Amazon and Jimmy's tomorrow
okay tomorrow morning like 6:00 a.m. and
I'm like yep of course I remember right
I like no thought no I had no idea who's
gonna watch the kids Jackie had a job I
knew she was gonna have to call him sick
and you she wasn't gonna like that but I
went yeah of course of course
yeah absolutely I'm there you know but I
would have dragged my child into the
Amazon buyers office before I was said
yeah hold him please yeah there's an
iPad dude like Joe please right if you
have an HD 510 so so I was like yes
absolutely and
I went up there I'd never even seen the
line they'd been testing all this
they've done all this market research
about that where they wanted to go and
who they wanted their customer to be and
he's like so I stayed on the phone with
him into like 2:30 a.m. you know what I
mean like he's just trying to run me
through all this stuff he's like dude
good luck I can't get there but I have
these meetings they're valuable meanings
we can't blow him off so good luck and I
remember showing up to Amazon and just
being like this is next next level like
again this is what I want to do with my
life yeah how have I put myself here
somehow right right just just the energy
and the like and I don't know that I
would share the same views as everyone
worse there or anything like that but
like just the just the overall culture
of like where where I had seen retail
come from mm-hmm when I walked in I'm
like this is where retail is going all
right and and and it like instantly was
like this nostalgic like especially from
a small here's the ship to I'd fallen
off the ship I'd been floating around
floating in the ocean kind of like
getting sunny and growing a beard and
then all of a sudden I'm like well
losing a couple Wilson's along the way
and all sort of like wait here's here's
what's next right that the cruise ship
comes to comes to pick you up right yeah
so so how did that go you know be
mindful of not disclosing any
information but no no it went awesome I
remember staying in the room and I was
like hey uh and I mean I have to be
myself of course that and what other
option is there I was like hey so if I
look excited about this line it's
because I am I've never seen it either
so let's do this oh okay yeah I'm like I
know the brand I know the culture I had
all the stats you know a lot of these
big like Amazon zoomies they looked now
they're looking for what kind of how
many people can you draw on our store
how many how much traffic can you draw
to our site
what's your online following I know that
that's a big change from like back to
the day that okay what's cool what's
funny what's
yeah what so or like what like his Corey
duffel shredding it what's he wearing
yeah you know what I mean that that's
how it was for me fashion was influenced
not by that stuff but it was by like
whoever is killing it the most that's
who I'm gonna wear that like it ya know
exactly and this was very much like look
we're doing we have this many views we
have this many followers we have this
many and Amazon was was all over it and
was like yeah absolutely let's do this
and it with it was just very cool like I
remember I asked the buyer if he wanted
to go get lunch after that after the
meeting I'm like dude let's go grab
something to eat like I'd love to pick
your brain about this and and he didn't
have to I mean they had like like you
okay 30 minutes now and at 30 minutes
they're like hard stop I mean Zach he's
in movies like these reality TV shows
level it's like yep yep and um and he's
like he's like yeah I'm like you guys
probably have a couple places to eat
here right and he just yeah you can see
that building out the window okay he's
like yeah we own that building too
he's like see this building out the
other window is a gabion that one too
and I think they own like two or three
more now but it was so next level that I
was just like this is unreal super super
cool thing to experience well so we were
talking about yesterday we were talking
the phone now it's actually in the mall
we were getting some candles from Bath
and Body Works because they smell so
good
yeah white mint maybe yeah it's nice and
clean cool thanks good I'm there I'm
always self-conscious about the sans how
it's just I wish that it wasn't weird to
ask someone to be like hey man you like
a sense in here does it smell good new
like well what if they walk in you look
like hey bruh ya sensor huge but anyway
Bath & Body Works and I called you and
we're talking about kind of it's just
strange it feels weird in the mall you
know it's it's I had worked in the mall
I had at one point I had three jobs just
in the mall and so I would like get off
my shift here and I wanna go grab food
from the food court and I would walk
down over here and like change in the
service hallway on the way or in the
backroom you know sort of thing like
always we both lived in the mall and so
like the environment of it was very you
know honestly I want to say I wouldn't
have said it back then but but to me it
was very comfortable in Homelink to me
I know that that seems kind of weird cuz
you think of a mall that's that's in a
small town it's just kind of like quiet
background music and it seems
no that's cloud my sister ice skated
when I was a kid so I grew up Oh Boyd
Center in Clackamas Mall oh right right
right yeah so I I have a very
deep-seated yes love I think a lot of
people genuine love of the mall and of
what it what it represented which was
people coming together and and being
able to you know it was like a it was a
perk of life it was something that was
fun and and we used to treat it as such
yeah it was an outing to go to the mall
now we were talking about on the phone
yesterday now it's which I'm not
projecting that these are just a
terrible evil thing change is good
I'm just observing that it is certainly
so different we go to to the mall to go
directly to one store it's a chore yeah
it's a yeah it's it's all I've had it as
an errand and it used to be like hey you
want to go hang out at the mall yeah
sweet I mean when I was a kid we'd all
pile in the car and we'd all go to
Clackamas and we'd you did get something
good at the food court you'd hang around
you'd look for what's new you need to
meet people I mean when I was young it
was it was cool to go there and and and
meet people and talk to them other
skaters or something infadoos yeah yeah
absolutely absolutely
yeah thing yeah it's so weird how how
different it is now it's again I I don't
think that it's such a bad thing I am
curious where it where it's gonna go
though what do you think so the the B
and C I mean it's on its way out
but I wonder I don't just think they're
just gonna be empty buildings in five to
ten years I imagine usefulness you know
the company who owns like our mall isn't
it a huge company and they're you know
they should know isn't it so someone
just bought it actually though smaller
group of investors okay some local some
out of I think it's Arizona okay and and
are and have been talking about
redeveloping it I don't know any I don't
know any specifics I know while I was
there they always talked about
remodeling it - yeah so I think that's
kind of a constant like hey we're gonna
do that they used to bring in a map and
they show me all the photo and pose low
different stores and I'm like hey that's
great I can use paint too but who's
actually signed a lease here and right
well but you know I learned in talks
with yeah art but that's part of the
game right I mean they they want you to
stay they want you to so well so what do
you see for the future of of malls I
don't know I want to be optimistic that
there's going to be some sort of I mean
because I'm someone who shops on Amazon
I'm someone who shops online all the
time I love the Internet I think it's
great
although it's Christmas presents this
year of course yeah it's a lot less
havoc I was done and I was done hey do
you wonder what it does to to
communities if it's if it's a more of a
bad thing for small communities for
example well I think it's it's a shift
for sure yeah that's a very good
question
I think that it increases business and
in different different ways as far as it
is employing a lot of people to deliver
these packages it's employment you know
it it's employing a lot of people as far
as the areas where these distribution
centers open up is it a good thing is it
a bad thing
I don't I mean time will tell what kind
of hard to say yeah I think that the a
going somewhere in experiencing
something will never go away but we are
like that's the kind of creatures we are
we're gonna continue to go to Mexico or
Disneyland or because that's a that's a
good experience we feel good about it
and while we're there
typically we'll purchase something mmm
we want to take a part of that with us
and same as in our store we always
wanted someone to come in and feel good
first and then if they wanted to take a
part of that with them and and it was
kind of this we can add to their life
right and so I think that you'll see a
lot of the malls go more to experience
based you know strictly come in and buy
cool stuff I think is going away and
part of part of what uh and maybe I'll
share a market secret that I'm not
supposed to share but when I had the
meeting with zoomies the buyer is like
don't tell anybody but we we've never
sold
clothing
and footwear because we sell fun we've
always sold fun and we'll continue to
sell fun because that's something
everyone can wrap their head around and
it's something that it can can appeal to
everyone and and it makes sense and
they've continued to do pretty well well
yeah I remember you told me once I think
that they they design their layout to
implicate like a boys messy room kind of
like it we feel more comfortable there
if you're an average shopper that's that
age yep that's good though it's a I
think that they're much more in tune
with who they're who their consumer is
who's actually coming in and continue to
buy things than some other businesses
that are like oh it's all about the
brands we carry here it's all about the
like they were much more about the
experience in their store and the fact
that it fun fun and selling fun
what is a universal principle that it
yeah it just makes it ever change yeah
who doesn't want fun
well Amazon sells us time or the
illusion of time and and that's really
saying that idea that's that's been
super trendy I feel like as far as uber
goes they saw the illusion of time but
you'll see people in Vegas that are
standing there waiting for the ruber as
taxis drive by I mean but but they're
selling you the illusion of time and
that's really like for that one time is
your most valuable assets so I get it
but there's there's gonna be some
figuring I think there's going to be
some self correction as far as people
need those experiences they're healthy
things going to the mall was much more
about being their friends or meeting
people or socially getting in front of
people and I think that there's got to
be some way that the market will will
correct itself right to an extent yeah I
kind of do wonder you were saying
experiences I don't know I'm always
thinking of the daydream side of things
it would be cool if there was a new sort
of thing that's not even a thing at all
that that comes up in terms of maybe it
is a when we go shopping we make sure
that it's fun so we go to the mall I
don't know what that means you know
maybe it's a slip but you can't even get
into the front doors unless you slip and
slide in you know I don't know that's
always sounds a little to me so you're
an artist yeah so you're looking to
create something please put a puppet at
the entrance yeah
for like grandma's all ages like you
it's not an option like you can't walk
around it'll be some something infused
with the technology I'm sure yeah and
and I think that we are yeah without
going too far off into the weeds
I think virtual reality will will
supplement a lot of the experience based
base things and when they can when they
can take you across the world and
replicate the experience I think it's
like 90 some percent of the experience
to have the smells the touch to touch
the feeling of being there the printing
of the future is going to be a pretty
interesting beast and I think yeah I
think you're hitting on something as in
like it's gonna be something that none
of us are really quite right
comprehending right now that's kind of
where you know just as a general blanket
statement with all of like the
technology the AI the I mean even I'm
gonna say political system I think all
of it in my opinion I think in 10 to 15
years it's gonna be massively
unrecognizable yeah well obviously go
back 10 to 15 years remember history
yeah 2008 the cracker wait was it too so
2000 crash 2007 was well then the iPhone
was invented that tells you perspective
of of how different our world is I made
a post yesterday about about us just
kind of be in monkeys with magic boxes
in our hands you do not leave the house
without your phone it's part of you know
in not that long ago you know in 2007
dude what I was you you got home the
first thing you do is you check the
voicemail mm-hmm house you check around
as it played yeah you would you would
roam your house as it just plays over
and what would you even do I wonder like
what what do you do as your voicemail is
playing you think you're doing something
but you're not doing your picking stuff
up and putting it back down it I want to
be I want to be conscious every time I
didn't ask before we began are you good
on okay so let's let's roundabout with
of course I'm always you know not
knowledge is very much power we've
already given them a lot of knowledge
here I would like to maybe just kind of
end end it here with a little advice for
younger people who are still working in
retail something that that Shaylee and I
have noticed
when we go to let's say you know
Vancouver Mall or Portland Mall or even
when I'm traveling around I go to
different malls the person beyond the
counter that you know their heart and
soul is not in it the way that me and my
co-workers were and I'm not trying to
say that like you're doing it wrong but
I'm saying this world is different yeah
this world is different and they're kind
of in here like you said yesterday we
were talking on the phone we mentioned
it like they don't want to be there at
all and I think that to me there's a lot
of that that could we could see this as
that's maybe that's just the introvert
side of you and you should push against
that a little bit so I just want to
anybody who is currently working in a
retail store and you feel like you just
hate it and you don't really want to put
your love and your passion into the
designs and the displays and the
customers and all these things I think
you should I would be willing to bet
that Bob thinks you should absolutely I
think that what gets missed is is that
your first job is really an opportunity
and I don't think that we have a no it
really comes down to the companies
recognizing that training people to be
better people is something that we're
missing we treat we train them to be
better employees we give them a whole
bunch of stuff but we don't explain to
them why how this applies to your life
long term this job this ability to do
the trial and error to to enhance your
social skills and my goodness to do know
in an environment that's fun okay I I
loved the fact that I got to come inside
I wasn't picking up a shovel of folding
a cotton shirt and talking about
something that I liked it and and above
and beyond that I didn't even if I
wasn't super passionate about a product
or a shoe or we could we could find
common ground and I could learn why you
were and I could try I could either
apply that to my life or I could or I
could realize that's not for me but we
should really be explaining to people
like that this is very valuable to you
yes it pulls you away from your phone
and I'm sure that we could dive into
that rabbit hole for a very long time
there was a huge we we struggled as an
employer to
keep employees by telling them their
phone had to be turned off and in the
back that was almost too far for them
they almost would pass up the job I
don't know these day can you do that now
is that a thing that I doesn't fly well
I wonder I don't know maybe I know it
doesn't fly well of course and and I
think that we we feel disconnected and
we get it gives people anxiety and they
don't realize that sometimes that's
that's not a bad thing recognize why
you're getting that anxiety definitely
learn something about yourself and live
in the present it gives you a very good
opportunity someone explained to me a
long time ago he said no matter what is
going wrong in your life if you can
leave it on the other side of the door
and work can be your escape from those
things cuz life is gonna give you drama
life's gonna give you less gonna give
you a list longer than you like of
things that you need to get done or
things that you're gonna have anxiety
about if you can get to work shut off
your phone and escape that and focus on
developing skills that will help enhance
that when you walk back out the door
work can be a vacation you literally can
escape the worries of life because you
can't do anything about them while
you're at work you can literally escape
those things and just enjoy yourself and
have fun and the success is the
byproduct so we're not we're not doing
enough people development we're doing a
lot of employee and I think that it's
puzzling to a lot of businesses they're
probably like well we have a great
training program and and we missed the
human aspect it's all school and we know
that school school wasn't for me I got
through high school but school is so
confining and I had to learn so much
stuff that I'm like I'm not interested
in this I don't feel like this is gonna
apply some of it has some of it hasn't
but but I want but I'm also very
motivated and driven person and so it
just didn't fit in that in that box and
I think we we missed the human element
of of training people dude I absolutely
agree I think that I always think of
things like why does people you have
your herd of simon Sinek he's a he's a
leadership motivational type speaker but
he goes around companies
and does a job that just seems
phenomenal as he goes in revamps
companies when they don't know what's
going on they're like these things are
good or they're their dynamics between
humans aren't going well the culture the
culture the dynamics between see one of
the most important parts of your
business I know but it's crazy how the
most profoundly changes these huge
businesses by going in and sometimes you
know speaking for 45 minutes and then
sometimes obviously having like a
weekend course or whatever but I think I
think that it's a good challenging
yourself in starting a job when you're
in these jobs and not seeing it as how
as how do I do this job the best or how
do I pretend to love this job or how do
I love this job like when you're when
you're doing it say what can I mine from
this opportunity and a lot of that is is
people if you're working in the customer
service a lot of times we get caught up
in these like hello how are you today
have a good day and that thing read a
script yes in what life is just tell you
to read the script I mean I've been
there
don't don't don't go outside of our
confines don't edit I didn't stay I
didn't stay at those places I need it I
personally know that I have to be me
very happy and and so I've always stuck
around do you do you think that the what
how do we break this illusion of when I
go to say your you're working at Burger
King and I come up and I'm like hey
buddy how are you what's up man
and you're like I'm good sir what is
your order and I'm just trying to make
you talk to me I'm trying to make you
talk to me this is something I do I want
to you know I like to like I came out I
just want to let you know that I think
that you're a human and I do appreciate
that you take my order you know I'm like
whatever you make my life better how do
I use consumers how do we on both sides
how do we always remember that like hey
man like it I just like that little
whisper thing I was talking my like aunt
like your shoes like where can we as
listeners and individuals on both sides
of this cash register often do this
where can we insert these hey man I know
that this stuff is crazy and you're just
saying your thing but I appreciate you
thank you I think we could be more
grateful absolutely a big part of
first manager ever had told me we are
gonna thank everyone whether they bought
something or not for coming in our store
they didn't have to do that they didn't
we want to thank them without and a lot
of businesses miss this a lot of
employees miss this it becomes a you
versus me thing and I every aspect of my
life I of always questioned why does
anything have to be you versus me it
never has to be that it should be us we
should come together and figure this out
and we should both be grateful that we
were able to do that and that we were
able to work with each other you don't
have to like someone but you should be
grateful for the opportunity to to mine
the experience yeah dude I love that
that's beautiful I really actually I
totally entirely agree I think that we
should be grateful on both sides of the
cash register regardless of where it's
at
I think that we should both both meaning
on both sides of the cash register where
there's wherever this is in customer
service world just be more grateful be
grateful for the opportunity be grateful
for the thing that you're buying for the
money in your wallet that you're pulling
it out
I mean sometimes we get so caught up
with as we're having this transaction
with our right hand we're texting with
our left hand right you know there's
something that I started this little set
this thing a few minutes ago was Shaylee
and I noticed that a lot of the
employees don't do this well you know
something that I could do better on my
end is I could be like you know what
when I walk into PacSun or when I walk
into zoomies I'm gonna just try not to
touch my phone no matter what so I'm
gonna like I'm gonna try to bring them
out of their thing because I know that
I'm good at conversation and I know that
maybe I can remind them pull them out of
their day pull them out of the you know
as the employees pull them out of their
their script so well and the phone is a
fun it's a it's a light it's a fun it's
a it's a it's a distraction it's mine
candy it's very easy to be on your phone
watching things there's no chance of
rejection or putting your foot in your
mouth or if somebody if you're looking
at your phone right somebody in there
right well and and you're kind of
falling into that instinct of introvert
you're kind of like I'm busy I'm kind of
doing this and you know what I mean but
you're missing your experiences mm-hmm
you're looking at
something that I would say is mostly
fake yes honestly I think that I've come
to the conclusion that it most of it is
not real Marya as you talk to people and
and I've even the nuances of how someone
acts or their facial expressions or
their there's so much value there of
sitting down and talking to someone face
to face yeah and that that we are
completely going away from as a society
and and all that matters is how you
paint this story and it's a form of art
it is it's a skill and how you paint
this story to everyone else but there's
not but but at the end of the day
there's not as much substance I don't
think yeah a lot of content there's not
as much yeah
a lot of you know the word connection is
kind of been jumbled around like yeah
we're connected but are we really you
know we're we can be connected but we
don't feel connected and that's
something that you know like you knew me
before as like a pretty confident good
sales person but with a lot of gotting
in technology and all of my personal
issues you know starting to getting more
depressed and more like looking into my
phone and and then I would sure enough
be the person who's never interacting
with the employee I just got into that
cave and I know firsthand how easy it is
to not make that effort but what I do so
I can be the best version of myself and
so maybe I can inspire other people to
be to be the best version of themselves
as I say okay man you're walking into
the store let's put your chest out you
know you're a lobster right now you got
you got a good posture put your chest
out let's take your air pods out so they
know you're ready to listen there's
certain times when I'll you know of
course go shopping with headphones in
sometimes I don't think it's a huge deal
but I don't know sometimes when I feel
that I have a little extra give a little
extra to give I should so that's what I
do
so I think listeners be on both sides of
the register and just just communicate
and just just be open try a little more
and it feels really good of all the
years of experience that I've had doing
different things when you genuinely can
connect with someone when you can make
their life I've had so many people come
in and they're just kind of going
through life or they're just kind of
going through the day or and and I was
able to whether they bought something or
not they were able to leave my
store feeling good and if we could if if
we would recognize that and sometimes
I'd come in and I was having the worst
day but I would leave it at the door and
and even if it would even feel forced at
first sometimes like I was like but I
knew it was good for me and all of a
sudden I all of a sudden everything
would turn around and and and I'm not
sure that any technology can give us
that hmm that gut like I actually feel
really good yeah and and that's
something that I think that is missed
yeah and I and I miss a lot of that
interaction that that retail used to be
a very fun fun environment and it'll be
interesting to see how it comes full
circle and people people are gonna want
that experience with the things they're
buying the convenience of buying it now
through your big platforms is very
enticing but I think that there's
there's a huge opportunity for people to
figure out how to correctly put the
experience back in because it'll it'll
be something that if you told me right
now what it looked like I'd probably
tell you no way
usually the truth is more bizarre than
we it's gonna bring our minds yeah yeah
we're not gonna be able to conceptualize
it now but that's a that's you know
money is not the only currency and I I
do always say that but something I can
add to that now it's time it's not the
only currency as well you know think
about the things that you're doing you
know you're gonna go buy a shirt because
you have a good night planned tonight
well why not why not just slow it down
and not rush in and rush out why not be
like let's try to have a good experience
while I'm going to get the shirt for my
night out not just save all my fun for
the night out you know stuff like that
back to the journey man that's your
advice enjoy the journey no matter how
big or small if all you're thinking
about is going and getting the shirt and
you you're totally moving everything
aside you're missing reality you're
missing where you are and what you're
doing and and that's you talked about
yoga earlier that my favorite thing
about yoga and I actually do a lot of
people don't know this about me but I
actually do yoga I did it last night I
mean I feel rude that I just like
steamrolled it didn't ask you I
let me tell you everything I know about
you know I know I probably s for asking
right yoga is one of those things that
pulls you into the present know it yeah
it's it pulls you into yourself and it
pulls you into the present and it mixes
it doesn't forget that you are like
biologically all of the stuff ties
together fitness your mental health ear
and and and all of that stuff it kind
highs it all together and and I think I
would recommend it to anybody I find it
very medicinal when you first started
did you do like YouTube or do you have
anything that no it was a free class at
my gym EPIK if the reason I started
doing yoga it was called synergy and it
was like a mix between a cardio and a
yoga and I had read many articles about
snowboarders I wanted to be a
professional snowboarder the first when
I was young I'd read many articles about
snowboarders being able to walk away
from something that would have taken
about for a little season because of the
agility that it gives you when you
stretch your body out so they'd be able
to fall and actually roll out of a lot
of things yeah scorpions Wow right so
they'd be able to stretch in ways that
before they weren't and now that they
they could and it would keep them from
being injured and best shape ever I
remember I woke up the next day after
the first class I took and I felt like
I'd had the flu for two weeks because it
releases all those toxins in your body
oh my gosh yeah and I mean I was like
what the heck is this and and a lot of
things that bring it bring discomfort to
me I tend to go back to I don't know if
I think that I don't know if that I
don't know if I'm saying that a very
good or healthy way but a lot of things
everything he loves on the other side of
feared something like that right right
and so it's skateboarding same thing man
I would get hurt I mean the pavement
doesn't forgive and you'd fall and get
hurt and you but you were like this is
kind of exciting like I can continue to
get better at this and and I can and you
know the pain was part of like the
realism of what you were experiencing
right yeah for me it was always
challenging myself to get smarter and
better and man it would always just blow
my mind I would always be able to just
be like dude this is crazy this is a
piece of wood this was trees that we put
seven them together and we called those
plies and put some round things on like
and I'm doing this precise it's just so
morning is an art is an artful yeah it's
in the that's the best explanation I've
ever heard and and it sees my head
around is it genuinely is this
expression yeah I think I think the
ultimate example that skateboarding and
snowboarding all extreme sports really a
lot of action sports watch them in slow
motion with a nice camera and you you
know instantly that that's art that's it
some of the most incredible human
individual art like you you can do the
same trick but you cannot do it exactly
the same way this guy did it even if you
tried it's just beautiful man Bob we got
to get going here but if you're down I
would love to have you on here more
often man you're such an intellectual
you're such a positive person it was it
was also just super great to catch up
with you and definitely anytime anytime
yeah all right bro well uh listeners
have a good rest of your day try to
remember that there's a human on the
other side of that register peace out
junkie I love podcasts
you